Finding Aid for R. W. Fleming papers, 1920-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Publications, speeches, and reports
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous remarks, statements and notes circa 1960-1975 (Box 42)
  - Reports
    - "Chancellor's Reports", The University of Wisconsin
      - 1965 (Box 42)
      - 1966 (Box 42)
      - 1967 (Box 42)
    - President's letters and reports, The University of Michigan 1968-1970 (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous 1959-1974 (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous works, 3 folders (Box 42)
- Personal and Autobiographical Materials
  Personal Papers and Autobiographical Material contains personal records, awards received, honorary diplomas and certificates, and appointment books. There are also several files pertaining to the writing and publication of Fleming's autobiography Tempests into rainbows: managing turbulence (1996).
  - Obituary and Funeral Service 2010 (Box 43)
  - Vita and other biographical materials (Box 43)
  - Autobiography, materials relating to research and publication of Fleming's book, 5 folders (Box 43)
  - Diplomas and certificates, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Awards, citations, and certificates, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Family matters
    - Carol (Quixley) Michler divorce correspondence 1959 (Box 43)
    - Guffin Estate correspondence 1954-1968, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Jeannett Fleming Boutwell (RWF's mother) 1972 (obituary and sympathy materials (Box 43)
    - Boutwell Estate correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - Passports (Box 43)
  - Daily appointment books 1952-1978, 29 volumes (Box 43)
  - Announcements and invitations (Box 43)
  - Schedules and Itineraries (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Ephemera (Box 43)
- Travel Records
  The Flemings traveled widely and often, for personal pleasure and on business. Included among the records are travel diaries and correspondence. Especially notable among the Fleming's travels are two trips to the People's Republic of China, the first taken by Robben Fleming in 1974 as part of a contingent of university presidents, and the second taken in 1976 by Sally Fleming as part of the University of Michigan delegation.
  - Summary of Fleming travel (Box 44)
  - Undated and miscellaneous (Box 44)
  - Passports (Box 44)
  - Chronological file
    - 1950 (Box 44)
    - 1956 (Box 44)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 44)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 44)
    - 1965 (Box 44)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 44)
    - 1969 (Box 44)
    - 1970 (Box 44)
    - 1971 (Box 44)
    - 1972 (Box 44)
    - 1974, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - 1975 (Box 44)
    - 1977 (Box 44)
    - 1978, 3 folders (Box 44)
    - 1970s (China visit and elsewhere) (Box 44)
    - 1991 (Danube cruise) travel diary (Box 44)
- Clippings and Scrapbooks
  Clippings and Scrapbooks are present for every phase of Fleming's life and career and comprise a useful and informative source on Fleming's activities.
  - Clippings
    - Undated (Box 45)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 45)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 45)
    - circa 1947-1952 re. Fleming while at the University of Wisconsin Industrial Relations Center (Box 45)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 45)
    - circa 1952-1964 re. Fleming while at the University of Illinois Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (Box 45)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 45)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 45)
    - circa 1964-1967 re. Fleming while Provost and later Chancellor at the University of Wisconsin, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - 1964 (Box 45)
    - 1965 (Box 45)
    - 1966 (Box 45)
    - circa 1967-1968 re. Fleming while President of the University of Michigan (Box 45)
    - 1967, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - 1968 (Box 45)
    - 1969 (Box 45)
    - 1970 (Box 45)
    - 1971 (Box 45)
    - 1972 (Box 45)
    - 1973 (Box 45)
    - 1974 (Box 45)
    - 1975 (Box 45)
    - 1976 (Box 45)
    - 1977 (Box 45)
    - 1978 (Box 45)
  - Fleming Family Clippings
    - circa 1914-1978 (Box 45)
  - Loose and unprocessed clippings (multiple folders) (Box 45)
  - Scrapbooks, R.W. Fleming and Fleming Family 1930-1972, 7 volumes (Box 46)
    (dates overlap, inclusive dates are penciled in on the first page of each volume)
  - Loose scrapbook materials
    - 1942 (Fleming-Quixley marriage) (Box 46)
    - 1948-1959 (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 46)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series consists of photographs and photograph albums from all phases of Fleming's career, but with special reference to his trips abroad.
  - Army service (Box 47)
  - Athletics (Box 47)
  - Early photographs, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Family, friends, and parents, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Fleming, Aldyth Quixley
    - Alone (Box 47)
    - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes (Box 47)
    - With others; in groups (Box 47)
  - Fleming children, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Fleming family (Box 47)
  - Fleming, R. W. (1980s activities) (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Portraits (Box 47)
  - Quixley family (Box 47)
  - Travel (miscellaneous) (Box 47)
  - Travel (Yugoslavia and Israel) 1977 (Box 47)
  - University of Wisconsin (Box 47)
  - University of Wisconsin (farewell dinner) 1952 (Box 47)
  - Album (loose) 1930s-1960s (Box 47)
  - Album (loose) 1941-1963 (Box 47)
  - Album (loose) 1942 (Box 47)
  - Album (unidentified), 19th century (Box 47)
  - Later photographs and miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Albums: Professional, family and social, 7 volumes (Box 48)
  - Album of trip to China February 7-29, 1976 (Box 50)
  - Album / Scrapbook 1942-1944 (Box 50)
  - Album of trip to Taiwan March 27-April 3, 1976 (Box 50)
  - Family photographs (2) (Box 51)
  - Childhood pictures (includes negatives) (Box 51)
  - Family, Friends and Parents (Box 51)
  - Family (Photo album), 6 folders (Box 51)
  - Fleming children 1952 (Box 51)
  - Illinois 1954- (Box 51)
  - Military 1942- (Box 51)
  - Portraits and photos of RWF (includes negatives), 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Relatives--Great-grandmother (Box 51)
  - Robben and Sally, early years (Beloit, Lake Delevan, Rockford, Washington) and Army friends 1930s-1940s (Box 51)
  - Rose Bowl 1970 (Box 51)
  - Robben Fleming's mother with family and 2nd husband, Paul Bontwell (Box 51)
  - Sally Fleming and Sally's family (Box 51)
  - University of Michigan (Box 51)
  - "Photos of Bob" 1981 (Box 51)
  - Photos (including Washington, DC) 1970s (Box 51)
  - Photos (including Saudi Arabia) 1970s-2002 (Box 51)
  - Scrapbook contents 1970s-1980s (Box 51)
  - Pastel portraits of son and daughter (Folder 1)
  - Officer candidates, Fort Custer 1940s (Folder 1)
  - Portrait of Fleming, Aldyth, and friends in medical uniforms 1938 (Folder 1)
  - Portrait of Robben Wright Fleming 1930s (Folder 1)
- Other visual and audio materials
  The collection concludes with a miscellanea of sound recording and videotapes of events at which Fleming either participated or at which he was honored.
  - Sound recordings (Box 49)
    - Robben Wright Fleming's inauguration ceremonies, 1968 March 11, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85232-SR-1-1]; mp3 file; (Robben Fleming inauguration ceremonies including invocation, speeches from regents, members of the Alumni Association.)
        [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
    - University of Michigan Law Club Evening Dinner, 1978 October 27, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
      - [Part 1], [85232-SR-2-1]; mp3 file; (Various speakers giving speeches about Robben Fleming on his accomplishments at the University of Michigan.)
    - Board of Trustees dinner program honoring Chancellor and Mrs. J. Roscoe Miller June 13, 1974, 1 audiocassettes (Box 49)
    - Concordia University, Montreal November 18, 1982 (Box 49)
  - Videotapes
    - "An Afternoon with the Presidents" November 10, 1982, VHS tape (Box 49)
    - Dedication ceremony of a Fleming Room at the University of Illinois Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, VHS tape (Box 49)
    - Cornell Cooperative Extension service: discussion with Frank Rhodes and RWF, VHS videotape (Box 49)
Related Material
As noted, the best source of information for the administration of Robben Fleming as President of The University of Michigan are the records of the Office of the President. Additionally, the researcher should note that although many of the letters are addressed to both Robben and Sally Fleming, there is a separate Sally Fleming collection documenting her interests and activities. A 1989 interview with Fleming concerning his career at the University of Michigan is located within the Historica Critica collection.